react a javascript library for building
user interfaces developed at facebook
and released in 2013 it's safe to say
react has been the most influential ui
library of recent memory we use it to
build components that represent logical
reusable parts of the ui the beauty of
react is that the simplicity of building
a component has been brought down to its
theoretical minimum it's just a
javascript function it's so easy a
caveman could do it the return value
from this function is your html or ui
which is written in a special syntax
called jsx allowing you to easily
combine javascript with html markup if
you want to pass data into a component
you simply pass it a props argument
which you can then reference inside the
function body or in the ui using braces
if the value changes react will react to
update the ui if we want to give our
component its own internal state we can
use the state hook the hook is just a
function that returns a value as well as
a function to change the value in this
case count is our reactive state and
setcount will change the state when used
in the template the count will always
show the most recent value then we can
bind set count to a button click event
so the user can change the state react
provides a variety of other built-in
hooks to handle common use cases but the
main reason you might want to use react
is not the library itself but the
massive ecosystem that surrounds it
react itself doesn't care about routing
state management animation or anything
like that instead it lets those concerns
evolve naturally within the open source
community no matter what you're trying
to do there's very likely a good
supporting library to help you get it
done need a static site you have gatsby
need server side rendering you have next
for animation you have spring for forums
you have formic state management you've
got redux mobx flux recoil x state and
more you have an endless supply of
choices to get things done the way you
like it as an added bonus once you have
reactdown you can easily jump into react
native and start building mobile apps
and it's no surprise that knowing this
little ui library is one of the most
in-demand skills for front-end
developers today this has been react in
100 seconds if you want to see more
short videos like this make sure to like
and subscribe and check out more
advanced react content on fire ship i o
and if you're curious how i make these
videos make sure to check out my new
personal channel and video on that topic
thanks for watching and i will see you
in the next one